Downloaded from
YTS.MX
[gentle piano music]
Official YIFY movies site:
YTS.MX
[inaudible]
[audience cheering]
[piano music grows warmer]
[Shawn Mendes] You first get on the stage,
and ego comes rushing in.
And it goes, "Don't mess up,
'cause you're the man.
Everyone's saying you're the man,
so don't mess up."
So you get to the mic,
and your first note is flat.
[chuckles] Always.
And then about 30 seconds in, you go...
"Oh, yeah,
I'm just a guy and I love music."
And your whole body releases.
And I just let go
and I look around, and I'm just like...
"Just do this.
Drop the ego.
Time to surrender."
[audience cheering]
[shower running]
[warm music creeping in]
[typing on phone]
[automated female voice]
Ever since I was about ten years old,
I was obsessed
with being really good at things.
[typing on phone]
That my worth is based on what I do.
And that can lead to a dark place.
[typing on phone]
My voice hit its breaking point
at the end of this tour,
-and I'm using my phone to talk.
-[playing melody]
Last night reminded me...
I'm not invincible.
[audience cheering]
[Shawn playing "Use Somebody"]
♪ Say whoa-oh-oh ♪
Sing!
[audience] ♪ Whoa-oh-oh ♪
♪ Say whoa-oh-oh ♪
Louder!
[audience] ♪ Whoa-oh-oh ♪
♪ Say yeah ♪
Scream it!
-[stamps foot]
-[audience] ♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Now oh-oh-oh
Oh, yeah ♪
-[stamping foot]
-[audience clapping]
No matter how fast I get,
do not stop clapping, all right?
Here we go! Clap those hands! Clap!
[audience clapping]
Faster!
[clapping and music accelerate]
[audience cheering loudly]
-[plays slowly]
-[audience cheering]
[gentle instrumental music]
[audience cheering loudly]
-[man] Hey, uh, good one.
-[Shawn] Thank you, brother.
Give us a hug.
[indistinct chatter]
-Thank you so much.
-[man 1] Let's go. Let's motor up.
-We've got an interview outside.
-[man 2] I'm not done with it.
[woman] You're gonna make a left
when you come out
and go through the lights.
-[Shawn] Thank you. Thank you.
-[woman 1] Bye!
[woman 2] I love you! I love you!
-[objects clattering]
-[man 1] Right there.
A little further. Right there.
[man 2] Just keep an eye...
I can't see the monitor...
So just keep an eye on the recording.
[softly] ♪ Oh, no, there it goes
Start another fire ♪
♪ Baby, oh, no, no ♪
[vocalizing a scale]
Hey, Cez, Jocelyn's gonna come.
I told her to be here for 11:50.
[man] All right.
[male interviewer] So, this thing
you start doing in your bedroom,
making Vines for the love of it...
Is it hard to protect
that pure thing that started it all?
[exhales deeply]
[gentle piano music]
[Karen Mendes] Come on, Shawn, let's go!
Time to go in!
Get up.
[Shawn] As a kid, when you look at someone
and you're like, "This is my dream..."
And someone goes, "That's a stupid dream,"
you'd be like,
"Oh, yeah, it is a stupid dream."
When I got into school...
Ms. Parker,
she was the vocal class teacher,
and I told her, "I want to be a singer.
I want to be...
I want to be an artist." You know?
And she had no hesitation to believe me.
My parents, my friends...
Nobody looked at me and said,
"You're crazy."
Everybody was like, "Go for it."
[strumming melody]
[Manny] He sounds better
all the time now.
With more practice like he's had...
[Karen] Hey!
-We love you, Shawn Mendes!
-I'm excited!
[indistinct conversation]
[Manny] This is larger than I thought.
[man] Yeah.
-[man] Can he hear it?
-No. No, no. Nothing can be heard.
[Manny] He may not like being filmed.
He's saying hello.
-Hi.
-[Shawn] He can't be filmed.
-[Manny] This ain't going anywhere.
-Okay.
Hey, Mom?
What do you say now?
It is nuts.
What, even to go to the bathroom,
he has to go with security.
-[woman] Oh, my God!
-[women screaming]
[woman] Oh, my God!
Oh, my God!
I love you!
[Manny] Did you see that?
-"I love you"? Holy moly.
-[Karen laughs]
[women cheering] Hi!
-You're not embarrassed of what?
-I'm nervous now.
I wasn't nervous until now.
Can we go back there?
[Manny] Hold on. Stay with me.
-[man] Give it up for Shawn Mendes!
-[audience cheering]
[Shawn playing "Give Me Love"]
♪ Give a little time to me ♪
♪ We'll burn this out ♪
♪ We'll play hide and seek ♪
♪ To turn this around ♪
♪ Oh, what I want is the taste
That your lips allow ♪
Do I have anyone from outside of Ontario?
-Where are you guys from?
-Michigan.
Michigan!
Holy...
Crazy.
[playing "Say Something"]
♪ Say something
I'm giving up on you ♪
I think I'd heard A Great Big World,
"Say Something" for the first time,
and I was like,
"Wow, that's a really great song."
Googled it...
and one of the first search results
was Shawn's cover of the song.
[playing "Say Something"]
♪ Say something
I'm giving up on you ♪
[Gertler] I was taken aback a bit.
It was like, "This is really incredible."
Reached out,
and we FaceTimed Shawn and his mom.
Immediately, Shawn just starts
grilling us with questions
about how the music business works,
why he might need a manager.
I just said to them,
I was honest,
"I don't know everything,
but I'm going to sit here
and spend every minute of my time
figuring it out with you."
[Shawn] I would always say to him,
"I need to get a band
'cause I'll sound bad on my own,"
and he'd say, "No.
Just get on the stage,
just you and the guitar."
Having the confidence
was all based off of those first couple
years of performing with just a guitar.
I went from a small bedroom in Pickering
to playing in front of a few
thousand people in a couple years.
[singing indistinctly]
-[audience cheering]
-[electric guitar chords resonating]
[Shawn playing
"I Wanna Dance with Somebody"]
♪ I wanna dance with somebody ♪
♪ I wanna feel the heat with somebody ♪
♪ Yeah! I wanna dance with somebody ♪
♪ With somebody who loves me
Yeah ♪
♪ Oh, I wanna dance with somebody ♪
♪ I wanna feel the heat with somebody
Yeah ♪
♪ Oh! I wanna dance with somebody ♪
♪ With somebody who loves me ♪
It looks so cool.
This is what it's like
filming a documentary.
Here we go.
-[playing melody]
-[indistinct conversation]
I'm not ready to give this to Scott.
[man] He's not here.
It all stems from when I met him,
and he had these cool sunglasses on.
He said, "If you had a number one single,
I'll give them to you."
The first thing we did together
went number one.
It needs another melody.
Yeah, it's just, like...
♪ You say... ♪
[playing melody]
How's that?
♪ I don't wanna see my lie ♪
[Scott] Got it?
[vocalizing]
♪ ...my eyes ♪
♪ So I say that ♪
♪ I don't wanna see you cry ♪
[vocalizing]
In my room, there's this thing
that has the number of shows
that we're on and where we are.
Today it's at number eight, Copenhagen,
and it made me think
we're not even close to 100.
[man laughs]
But it also said Cologne, not Copenhagen.
-We're in Cologne.
-[Shawn] It said Cologne.
-Actually, it might have said Copenhagen.
-[all laughing]
But I want us to always
keep in mind that this is very special.
I'll say it, I know it'll get annoying,
but it truly is so special.
What we get to do is magical.
Everyone in there,
it's their first time seeing it,
every single time.
-No matter if it's show one or show 99.
-That's right.
It's their first time seeing it,
it's special, so thanks. Let's do it.
-Beautiful.
-Let's do it.
Everybody jump!
[audience singing indistinctly to music]
[Shawn] I used to look
at so many of my idols and be like,
"How can you ever be that?
They were born legendary."
That's just not the truth.
[audience cheering]
[Shawn] People are like, "What would you
be doing if this didn't happen?"
I feel puzzled by that question,
because I feel like
this is what I was going to do.
I'm in the Q&A yesterday.
This girl goes,
"How do I be a songwriter like you?"
I immediately
thought about saying that to my dad,
"I wanna be a songwriter."
He goes, "Can you write songs?"
I said, "I don't know."
He goes, "Write one."
I sat in my room
and I played guitar for seven hours.
My hands bled. I'd play again
and get better, and I'd practice.
And I'm not saying everyone has to be
so Olympic athlete about it.
I said that to her. I was like,
"Stop sitting here thinking about it.
You are a songwriter.
Now, go write songs."
[playing "Ruin"]
-Here we go!
-[audience cheering]
♪ No, I'm not trying
To ruin your happiness, baby ♪
♪ But, darling, don't you know
That I'm the only one, yeah ♪
New York!
["Can't Take My Eyes Off You"
playing on stereo]
♪ You're just too good to be true ♪
♪ Can't take my eyes off of you ♪
You don't hear songs that say,
"You're just too good to be true.
Can't take my eyes off of you."
["Can't Take My Eyes Off You"
continues playing]
Even, like, those trumpets going...
[imitating trumpets]
Like, all that trumpet stuff
is really cool, right?
Feels, like, so, like, grandiose.
There's something about that I think about
when it comes to the next album.
Something about, like, that, like...
feeling, that, like,
all-around, like, overdose of love.
[guitar strumming]
♪ Here I sleep in London ♪
♪ 'Cause I could spend
A hundred days in-- ♪
Could you go, "Counting back from 100,
so I can fall asleep faster"?
♪ Sleep in London
I count back from 100 ♪
-That's cool.
-Yeah.
I was feeling like a...
[Scott] Love the echo
after "Hello, hello."
♪ Hello, hello, hello
Can I get an echo? ♪
♪ Purple, red, and yellow ♪
[vocalizing]
[Scott] ♪ Head down on the pillow ♪
♪ Something that I... ♪
♪ When I'm not with you ♪
♪ I just close my eyes ♪
"All I have to do."
♪ All I have to do ♪
[both] ♪ Is dream, dream, dream, dream ♪
[man] Yeah.
[all] ♪ About you, about you, about you ♪
That's the one.
[recorded music-only track playing]
It sounds better without.
-[man 1] Without?
-[man 2] Sounds better.
♪ Hello, hello, hello
Can I hear an echo? ♪
♪ Purple, red, and yellow
I can't wait to get home ♪
♪ Head down on the pillow
Holding you is all I think about ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ When I'm a...
When I'm... ♪
Again.
♪ When I'm a... ♪
♪ When I'm apart from you ♪
♪ I just close my eyes ♪
♪ All I have to do ♪
Okay, George, punch me on "Close my eyes".
♪ Close my eyes
Close my eyes, close my eyes ♪
It's pretty cool,
she rents an apartment in West Village,
so we're staying there,
We wake up in the morning,
like, "This is fucked."
And we have to wake up
and both separately get in SUVs
to head to the same place.
-[man] Yeah.
-It's pretty cool.
I'm like, "I gotta leave at 8:30."
She's like, "Me too."
It's almost like living
a taste of a normal life
in the least normal-life way.
Getting all my clothes on
and running to the café for an Americano.
Then you guys pulled up, and I was like,
"Right, we're going to work."
-[man] How you doing?
-Good, how are you?
[drums tuning]
♪ I can't write one song
That's not about you, baby ♪
♪ Is it too late to tell you that ♪
♪ Everything means nothing
If I can't have you? ♪
♪ No ♪
♪ Every touch is ooh-la-la-la ♪
We go this way.
So, when I step this way,
what do I do with my arm?
Boom. So this hand, when you step over...
You step over here, boom.
-You look back...
-Love that.
...and then you come around...
-So--
-Okay, got it.
-You're going to the other side.
-No.
-All your weight is here.
-Yep.
And then, you know
about the outside edge...
This side?
[woman] Yeah, making sure that...
[strumming chords]
[slow, pensive music]
[Cabello] ♪ I love it
When you call me señorita ♪
♪ I wish I could pretend
I didn't need ya ♪
[inaudible]
Okay. Super cozy.
-Super cozy.
-Yeah.
[kisses] I love you.
-Do you know that?
-I know.
[kisses]
[man 1] Thank you, everyone, good to go.
Places. Let's start rehearsal, please.
[man 2] We're ready to roll
when you folks are ready.
[Shawn] Camila, she was in Fifth Harmony,
and we were both opening.
[chuckles] My very first tour ever.
And she was the act after me.
I was first in the lineup,
with the shortest set,
and then they went on.
Five years ago, man.
[Cabello] He was so...
super hyper-focused
on what he was doing.
I never saw him the whole tour.
He was constantly in and out of his bus,
playing guitar, writing songs with Geoff.
I thought he was cute, but I was like,
"He's... He's doing other stuff,
so whatever."
[laughs]
And then, I guess it must have been
about four or five years ago,
we were backstage
at this Taylor Swift show.
I went to his dressing room to say hi.
And we, like, started writing this song.
And then after that, we, like,
spent a lot of time with each other
because we had the song together
and we did
a whole Jingle Ball tour together.
And that's really when
the fucking saga started.
I really liked him.
I guess he liked me, but...
I don't really know. [laughs]
[Shawn] For the past four years,
just being friends
and not seeing each other very often
to finally being able to be together,
she was always there
to look out for me as a human being.
She's got my back, and I think
that's what your partner's for.
We're in New York, and my song
comes on the radio or something,
and the fact comes up
that it's about her.
And I'm like, "Yeah, it's about you.
Everything's about you.
They've always been about you."
She goes, "What do you mean?"
I'm like, "They're all about you.
Like, every song I ever wrote."
And I'm rhyming off the songs like,
"Treat You Better," all these songs.
She's like, "Oh, my God."
She literally had no idea.
This whole time,
I thought she, like, knew.
I don't think I'll be able
to write songs that really do it justice,
that can really capture
the things and the feelings with her.
I think it's like
when you see a moon or stars
and you try to take
a photo of it with your iPhone,
and then you just can't,
it just doesn't look good.
And you're like, "It's not
supposed to be captured." You know?
It's just supposed to be for us.
[Cabello] Want to do it again for fun,
stuff like that?
Play around just to get loose.
[vocalizing]
[both] ♪ I love it
When you call me señorita ♪
♪ I wish I could pretend
I didn't need ya ♪
♪ But every touch is ooh la la la ♪
♪ It's true, la la la ♪
♪ Ooh, I should be running ♪
♪ Ooh, you keep me coming for ya ♪
♪ Locked in the hotel ♪
♪ There's just some things
That never change ♪
♪ But friends don't know
The way you taste ♪
♪ You know it's been a long time coming
Don't you let me fall, oh ♪
[both]
♪ Ooh, when your lips undress me ♪
♪ Hooked on your tongue ♪
♪ Ooh, love, your kiss is deadly ♪
♪ Don't stop ♪
-[whispers] Boom. Boom, boom. Boom, boom.
-[exhales sharply]
-Yeah, yeah.
-[both laugh]
-[sighs]
Okay. Good. Let's sing another song.
What's a song for fun?
Literally, any song, but ours.
♪ It's not a silly little moment ♪
Fuck, yeah.
[both] ♪ It's not the storm
Before the calm ♪
♪ This is the deep and dying breath of ♪
♪ That we've been working on ♪
♪ We're going down ♪
♪ And you know that we're doomed ♪
♪ My dear, we're slow dancing
In a burning room ♪
[gentle piano music]
[man] Step back.
-[people clamoring]
-[man] Step back.
[women screaming]
Shawn! Shawn!
[camera shutters clicking]
[photographer] Shawn, all the way down.
Shawn! Shawn, right here for me, man.
Shawn!
Shawn, right here!
[man] Mr. Mendes!
Shawn, one more here.
[people continue screaming excitedly]
Oh, my God!
[gentle music continues]
[man] It's insane. That was insane!
That was a really calm red carpet.
[laughs] I'm serious.
-[man] That was calm?
-That was calm, dude.
[audience cheering loudly]
[Cabello] Wait, my, uh...
My shoe! My shoe!
Oh, no!
My shoe.
[Shawn] Is there a proper way to do this?
I swear, I'm gonna tie a double knot.
[woman] Who's ready?
[vocalizing]
♪ It meant something to ya ♪
[Cabello] ♪ Ooh, you keep me
Coming for ya ♪
Can I have water?
Come on, it's time, let's go.
[inaudible]
[audience cheering loudly]
[Shawn] At this moment in time,
during the summer
of whatever you want to name this summer,
during "Señorita"
and "If I Can't Have You"...
Camila and I are staying
in an apartment in NYC
for the very first time alone.
And making eggs and trying
to figure out how to use a Keurig.
Normal things, you know?
This is really cool,
to just be, like, a 21-year-old guy.
And getting older...
That's happening for me too.
[Cabello laughs]
[man] Give it up for Shawn Mendes!
[audience cheering loudly]
[slow, pensive music]
Camila Cabello, everybody!
[audience cheering]
[Shawn] I'm nervous.
Yeah, I feel anxious to go home right now.
[man] How long has it been?
Three and half months.
It's a long time.
I'm excited to have a couple days off
and be with friends and family.
Yeah. So excited.
I'm so lucky to have a friend like Brian.
He loves them anyway.
He works hard
at keeping me in the real world.
If we had our own FIFA cards,
you'd probably have--
-I'd have a high rating.
-You'd probably be 76 passing,
-I'd be 82.
-Not a chance.
-I'd be rated a 93, you'd be rated an 87.
-[snorts, laughs]
What's Ronaldo?
Ronaldo? I think Ronaldo's a 94.
-Yeah, I'm a 93.
-[both laugh]
Without him, I don't know,
I'd probably be, like, pretty crazy.
Can you match my tone?
That's my question.
[flatly] ♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
[laughs]
[Shawn] He just connects me
with friends from home.
I'm probably closer with my friends
from home now than ever.
-Oh!
-They were all supporting me
from the first time
"Life of the Party" came out,
and now we're here together.
I want them to look around
and be proud of it
and be like,
"This is just as much ours as it is his."
"Look, guys, we made it.
How beautiful is this?"
All right, bedroom.
You did me great. Thanks.
I'll see you next time.
Thank God I'm leaving you.
Double guitar.
Let's go, bro.
Good to see you, man.
-Good to see you, welcome back.
-Thank you.
You rock! You rock! You rock!
[delicate music playing]
Welcome.
-It's been unlocked for three months.
-[Brian laughs]
Let's go.
Welcome to my cozy house!
It smells great in here.
Okay, everything seems right.
How's your room, Brian? Seems right?
[Brian] Checks out.
[Shawn] Everything checks out?
[Brian] Oh, yeah.
[alarm beeping]
An alarm!
[Brian] Fuck.
Wow, the worst shit.
[laughs]
Hasn't been home for so long.
[Shawn] This view is, like,
the best view I have ever seen in Toronto.
Except for them building this gross thing.
What is that?
Oh, my God,
they're building a mall or something.
This is pretty cool, eh? Rogers Centre?
[Brian] You can see it from here.
You can see the Rogers Centre
from my apartment.
I can see it from my bedroom window
when I wake up in the morning.
That's kind of insane
to think about that I'm playing there.
Damn.
[Shawn] Hello, Mom.
-How's it going?
-Good, we're just headed down.
Okay, I'm just trying to...
'Cause I spoke to Amy,
the coordinator following you,
but she wasn't sure
if you were going to Whitby
to get Aaliyah.
I'm headed to pick her up.
I'm 30 minutes from her.
All right, babe. See you soon.
What up!
[chuckles]
Hey.
-My daughter's a big fan of yours.
-[laughs]
You wanna flip that on selfie mode?
Tell your daughter hi.
-Can you say hi? Her name is Berina.
-Berina, I love you.
-Thanks, buddy.
-Yeah, man.
Canadian love right there.
Hello.
You had a first day of school today.
That's why you're in your outfit.
-I like wearing this all the time.
-I didn't think about it.
[gentle music]
Look at this shit.
Man, this is our... This is our field.
Brian and I fully, 100% climbed up that.
Swear to God.
He told you?
This is our turf, man.
The turf we talked about.
-[man chuckles]
-Like, this is where we grew up.
That's why when we talk about Pickering,
we're obsessed with it.
Look at this.
-[man] Yo.
-Look, I brought Tainy to the turf, bro.
-No! What?
-[chuckles]
Wow.
How is it?
It's fucking great, man.
-Man, I should've came.
-I know.
Wow, looks amazing.
Dude, it's incredible here right now.
[gentle music continues]
[Aaliyah] When he started singing,
he wasn't the greatest.
I was like, "Let's see where this goes."
It was just constant noise at my house.
So annoying.
Like, it was awful.
I asked him
if he wanted to be famous one day,
and he, like,
shut the whole idea down so fast.
He was like, "No, I don't want
to be famous. It seems awful."
I don't know if he remembers that,
but I remember that like it was yesterday.
I remember I asked you
when you first started singing
if you wanted to become famous,
and you, like, were disgusted by the idea.
-I was?
-Yeah.
You were like, "No,
I would never wanna be famous,
like, that lifestyle."
-Probably.
-I remember you saying that.
You said it all the time.
'Cause... Obviously, you got good,
and you started getting noticed,
so I was like,
"You're gonna become famous."
You were, like,
"I don't wanna be famous."
I don't remember that.
We talked about it
all the time in the office.
Well, I obviously changed my mind.
I used to...
This door here...
We'd finish school off...
and everyone would come rushing down
and just hang outside
on this front thing on a Friday.
Two hundred people hanging out here,
trying to figure out the plans for Friday.
-It was so good.
-We don't do that.
[Shawn] Everyone did that.
[chuckles]
Welcome home, guys.
[pensive music]
-[Aaliyah] I got to do homework.
-[both chuckle]
[Karen] Oh!
[indistinct conversation]
[Shawn] Guys, welcome.
This is my home!
[chuckles]
Oh, my God.
So stupid.
The biggest plaque you've ever seen.
I've, like, been in every bedroom,
but this is my bedroom. Welcome.
[laughs]
This is the room
I recorded all the Vines and stuff in.
Pretty small in here, right?
This is it, bro.
[clears throat]
This pillow is... Fuck.
They smell good.
Mmm!
[inhales deeply]
Whoa. That was actually
really overwhelming. [chuckles]
Mom, I feel like
I kind of live here again.
-[Karen] He only comes here to eat.
-Not true.
-Yes, you do.
-What is this?
Every time you walk in you're hungry.
Look at this. Look at this sweater.
-It's Camila.
-Oh, my God.
-My girlfriend. Do you know about her?
-No, I don't, Shawn.
You make more money than all of us,
-and you come here to eat for free?
-Oh, yeah.
-[in Portuguese] How are you?
-[in English] Hey, buddy.
[chuckles]
It's crazy. This is the most time
I've spent at home in,
like, a year, probably,
in the last three days, right?
-For sure.
-Every time he comes,
I try to get him to stay.
And you actually got to relax.
Usually, he comes in and eats, says,
"I'm not staying long."
We might get him to watch a movie.
That's it.
Christmas Eve, he stays.
He spends the night to wait
for Santa Claus with Aaliyah.
-That's right.
-Then they get up in the morning,
and Santa Claus has left
all the gifts under the tree.
-Isn't that right?
-She doesn't drop it.
-No.
-Santa Claus is real.
-Yeah.
-Right?
-If you believe it.
-I believe.
Yeah, that's it.
-You went to the stadium today?
-[Manny] I went yesterday.
-It's big in there.
-It's massive.
I don't want to see anything
until I walk in tomorrow.
-I'm gonna be there tomorrow.
-What time?
-Probably around noon.
-Around noon?
In time for catering,
that's why I'll be there.
-[laughs]
-Good, good, good. Smart guy.
This is, like, something else too.
I wrote this
in the green room the other day.
[on recording] ♪ I know you want
To say goodbye ♪
No lyrics.
[indistinct]
♪ The feeling I just can't deny ♪
♪ I know you want to get along ♪
[indistinct]
♪ And I know it's kind of sad, but still ♪
♪ I just got to tell you
That I'm gonna take you down ♪
♪ It's always been you
It's always been you ♪
I want to write a song
that's orchestra heaven,
massive drums, and...
[imitates buzzing drum]
And then really quiet,
my vocal just goes...
♪ It's always been you
It's always been you ♪
[imitates buzzing drum noise]
My car is driving itself right now.
[man chuckles]
[playing gentle melody]
[Shawn] Yesterday we were watching
videos of us when we were, like, 16.
We both got so caught up in it.
We looked at each other and were like,
"I don't feel good."
'Cause we were taken right back
to that insecure, unsure 15-year-old.
And I just felt like, "Wow,
she really understands that feeling."
We looked at each other and said,
"We feel weird right now, huh?"
And she's like, "Yeah, we do."
And I'm like, "I'm so happy you know why,
'cause I don't know if I could
explain this well to others."
[playing gentle melody]
Sounds like your heart.
Feels like my heart, yeah.
Yeah, I went through a phase where
I used to write this over and over.
"I control my brain with my voice."
"I sing with no tension."
"My chest voice is strong and healthy."
This was...
two weeks before we put Rogers Centre
on sale, November 24th, 2018.
I wrote... "Here we go.
I will sell out the Rogers Centre."
I remember I was in this condo.
-And on November 28th... 25th, 2018.
-You wrote...
-[both] "I sold out the Rogers Centre."
-[chuckles]
That's why it worked.
I wrote it in my manifestation journal.
-Yeah, it was persistent.
-This is persistency right here.
[man] You did that thing where you're...
[Shawn] I think Rogers Centre
was always a goal of mine.
'Cause when I started playing music,
I'd drive by it every day
and say,
"I'm gonna play there one day."
Jesus Christ.
-[man] Whoo! Yeah, man!
-[both laugh]
[Shawn] Oh, my God!
What is going on?
I don't even know what to look at.
-Where's the stage?
-[man] There.
[chuckles] This is crazy.
It's kind of big.
-[man] Fuckin' huge.
-[laughs]
This is insane!
[pensive music]
The stage feels small.
Does the stage look small here?
Does the stage feel small?
I know I can't put a new stage in, but...
-Brother, look what you did.
-[laughs]
I walked on, immediately
I was like, "Is the stage small?"
-Just take it in.
-Actually feels like a city here.
Look at it.
I'm looking at the Rogers Centre, and
for the first time I'm getting nervous.
On the street, the coffee guy says
he's coming to the show.
My door guy at my condo says,
"I'm coming to the show."
This is a real family thing.
This isn't like...
playing your biggest show
of all time. It's more like,
"This is incredible.
We're in his hometown.
There's so much love surrounded.
He's playing a show.
It's also in the biggest stadium
in the country."
[people cheering loudly]
♪ Let's get lost tonight ♪
♪ Baby, me and you ♪
♪ I can't seem to get you off my mind ♪
♪ Get you off my mind ♪
[people cheering in distance]
I feel crazy. I've never felt like this.
I feel crazy.
[people cheering loudly]
[opening music playing]
It's loud.
[music intensifies]
[cheering intensifies]
Fuck!
[cheering grows louder]
[intro music starts]
♪ All it'd take is one flight ♪
♪ We'd be in the same time zone, yeah ♪
♪ Looking through your timeline ♪
♪ Seeing all the rainbows, I ♪
♪ I got an idea ♪
♪ And I know that it sounds crazy, baby ♪
♪ I wanna see ya ♪
♪ Oh, I gotta ask ♪
♪ Do you got plans tonight? ♪
Sing along!
[audience] ♪ I'm a couple hundred miles
From Japan and I ♪
♪ I was thinkin' I could fly
To your hotel tonight ♪
♪ 'Cause I can't get you off my mind ♪
♪ Can't get you off my mind
Can't get you off my mind ♪
Here we go!
♪ Let's get lost tonight ♪
♪ Let's get lost tonight ♪
♪ Baby, you and ♪
♪ I can't seem to get you off my mind ♪
[Shawn] For this whole year
and most of your life,
it feels like you've been
anticipating a show like this.
You're standing in front of a crowd
of 50,000 people.
And it feels completely surreal.
It's like your feet are floating
off the ground.
It's kind of pure magic
from start to finish.
♪ When you're high up above
Or down below ♪
♪ When you're too in love to let it go ♪
♪ But if you never try
Then you'll never know ♪
♪ Just what you're worth ♪
Everybody all together. Here we go.
-♪ 'Cause lights will... ♪
-♪ 'Cause lights will guide you home ♪
♪ And ignite your bones ♪
♪ And I will try to fix you ♪
I love you so much. Thank you.
[audience cheering loudly]
[Shawn] I just felt like there was this
real sense of love in the room that night.
Toronto, I love you so much
with all of my heart. Thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you so much for having us.
[people whooping]
[cheering continues]
[inaudible]
-Great.
-[people whooping]
[man] Manny!
I was so mad. I thought you guys left.
Oh, Shawn!
[indistinct chatter]
Nothing better than that, Shawn.
-Oh, Shawn, I am so proud of you.
-Thank you.
-You know me, I cry a lot.
-[laughing]
-[women cheering]
-[woman] Shawn!
Thank you!
Are we in the right car?
[on recording]
♪ Ooh, your body's like an ocean ♪
-Huh?
-I have her vocals separate, too,
so we can pull 'em down if we need to.
-It's all over two.
-Yeah.
[on recording]
♪ Ooh, what do you desire... ♪
[engineer] The backgrounds right now...
[Shawn] What happens to me
when I'm on tour is
I get obsessed with chords.
I kept playing this.
[plays soothing progression]
♪ Ooh, your body's like an ocean ♪
♪ I'm devoted ♪
♪ I'll do
I'll do it for you ♪
♪ Run my hands around you ♪
♪ Ooh, teach me how to ♪
♪ Touch you, kiss, caress you
And squeeze ♪
♪ Teach me how to love ♪
Something like that.
[all] ♪ Ooh, teach me how to ♪
♪ Touch you, tease
Caress you and please you ♪
♪ Teach me how to love ♪
-Yeah.
-To go from the unison to the harmony,
I'd be like, "Can't do it."
-[chuckling]
-I had to repeat it.
Most of the time I have to play
the piano part into the track.
♪ How to love ♪
-♪ How to love ♪
-[woman] Mmm-hmm.
♪ How to love ♪
I might come in there with you
'cause it's fun.
♪ Teach me, teach me, teach me
How to love ♪
♪ How to love ♪
♪ Teach me, teach me, teach me
How to love ♪
Let's go once more.
Go again.
I'm gonna take a listen for a sec.
'Cause we have
this individual line function...
[on recording] ♪ Teach me, teach me
Teach me how to love ♪
♪ How to love ♪
[vocalizing]
Yeah.
[Shawn] And we're missing the...
[vocalizes series of notes]
-Is anyone doing that note?
-♪ Ooh ♪
You are?
-Yeah.
-You're just quiet in here.
♪ Ooh... ♪
Where are you?
We'll just turn you up a little.
♪ Teach me how to ♪
Yeah, we need that.
[song playing]
♪ Teach me, teach me, teach me
How to love ♪
[plucking melody]
[Shawn] I've definitely always felt
the pressure to make music that's
better than what I've done before.
I feel this time around,
I'm in the studio...
kind of just being like,
"Okay, whatever comes, comes."
[playing with melodies and chords]
We recording, George?
[Shawn] You have to not only accept
imperfection but embrace imperfection,
because that imperfection in that moment
is what turns into magic in the next.
♪ Look up at the stars ♪
♪ They're like pieces of art ♪
♪ Floating above the planet ♪
♪ You know we've come so far ♪
♪ The universe is ours ♪
♪ And I'm not gonna let you down ♪
♪ It's a Friday night and streetlights ♪
♪ Are all saying your name ♪
♪ They always say your name ♪
♪ Before you go home
I should let you know ♪
♪ I'm so glad that you came ♪
♪ I know that we went late
No, no ♪
♪ But look up at the stars ♪
♪ They're like pieces of art ♪
♪ Floating above the planet ♪
♪ You know we've come so far ♪
♪ The universe is ours ♪
♪ And I'm not gonna let you down ♪
I wonder what else I can do.
[sighs]
Maybe I'm doing
a little too much on stage.
[Cez Darke] Maybe.
Maybe calm down a bit.
You've also added another song.
Two songs.
Two songs, basically.
-And the medley's longer.
-Yeah.
So you're working harder.
[audience cheering]
[playing psychedelic solo]
[singing indistinctly]
[singing scream]
♪ You rocked me ♪
[raspy voice] London, how you doing?
Beautiful!
♪ I'm tripping over myself... ♪
[voice cutting off]
[audience cheering]
I'm so sorry, guys. My voice is
cutting out on me so much tonight.
I'll need your help as much as I can.
I promise to sing my heart out,
but I only got what I got in my voice,
so thank you so much.
They're looping.
You tell me when you want to go.
Fucking hell, man. I just...
-What you just did just then...
-No, man, I...
It's insane.
[inaudible]
[pensive music]
[Shawn] We're on a 104-show tour, and...
half of me right now is like,
"Make sure you say you're grateful,"
because I am.
In the biggest way, I'm so grateful.
I love these performances.
I've never had more fun in my life, but...
[Shawn and Karen talk indistinctly]
I also want to hang with my parents,
watch movies.
You're gonna do a tree at my house?
Yeah. I'll do your tree, but nothing else.
-Yeah.
-...school.
[Shawn] Drive around a suburb,
lay on a soccer field...
smoke a joint
and stare at the stars with my friends
and, like, eat some beef jerky.
[laughs]
And, like, really, like,
small-town thoughts.
You know, those things are like...
I think I miss that
a little bit right now.
It's pretty intense all the time.
I really think about that a lot.
If I tell the world
that I'm just a normal human,
are they going to stop
coming to the shows
and listening to the music, and, like,
is all the craziness going to stop?
Then you're like,
"Maybe I shouldn't tell them.
I should keep the trick up.
Maybe I should pretend that
I'm Superman for a little bit longer."
[gentle piano music]
Just played.
Writing a little message on Instagram.
"Feeling overwhelmed by life today.
I'm right here right now,
and it's beautiful.
And it's so beautiful.
And it's so beautiful."
That's all I got for you.
[distant Latin music playing]
[Shawn playing melody on guitar]
I've been trying to figure it out
since it started, you know,
and I have a billion different ways...
People'll be like, "Why'd this happen
to you?" I have a lot of logical answers,
but none of them are satisfying, you know?
-[Eric Vetro performing voice exercise]
-[Shawn repeating after him]
[voice exercising continues]
I'm constantly warming up,
and I'm constantly checking my voice
out of fear of the fact that...
one day I'm going to go to sing
and it's going to just not come out.
[Vetro] Open the back of your throat,
take a deep breath.
[Shawn performing vocal exercise]
[Vetro] Really loose and open.
[Shawn singing scale]
[vocalizing]
[voice rising to a high pitch]
♪ Yeah ♪
[playing "Youth"]
[all] ♪ You can't take my youth away ♪
♪ This soul of mine will never break ♪
[audience]
♪ As long as I wake up today ♪
♪ You can't take my youth away ♪
[Shawn] What are they doing?
[man] They're running 'cause they see
other people running.
Dude, the show's gonna be nuts.
They're screaming.
I wonder if the band's out there.
Maybe it's 'cause I just posted
the Instagram of the sunset.
Doesn't mean that I'm down there.
[indistinct conversations]
-Hi.
-This experience has been so good.
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
-I can't speak.
-It's okay.
It's so nice to meet you.
[indistinct]
Yeah.
[indistinct chatter]
You make me feel connected to you
and connected to people around me,
and I'm just so thankful, and I...
-Oh, my God.
-[laughs]
Should we take a photo?
[laughing joyfully]
[slow, gentle music]
[women screaming]
[Shawn] When you're pulling up to a hotel
in a country you've never been to,
and there's 1,000 people
outside waiting for you...
no matter how many times
you go through that, it feels...
like a dream.
I don't know
if that's ever going to feel normal.
if that's supposed to feel normal.
[woman sobbing and talking indistinctly]
I love you so much, thank you!
Thank you so much!
Thank you, Shawn! I love you!
I love you so much.
[speaking in Portuguese]
What's up, guys?
We're, uh... We're in Brazil
on the last leg of the tour.
I woke up feeling...
[clears throat] ...pretty sick today.
The day before I'm gonna play
two stadiums in São Paulo.
But you know what? It's okay because...
I watched some Kobe Bryant YouTube videos
and I feel great.
[clears throat]
[playing upbeat song on guitar]
-'Cause I had swelling on my right cord.
-Yeah, that's swollen.
Just wanna check.
I have volume if I wanna bring it back.
-Okay, you'll just--
-But I just am choosing not to. Yeah.
Yeah.
[inaudible]
[vocalizing]
[doctor speaking indistinctly]
Thank you so much.
[slow, reflecting music]
[vocalizing]
[Vetro] Hey, how's it going?
It's going. It's going.
Just listen to this. This is...
[vocalizing]
I don't know. It makes me very nervous.
What time is it there right now?
It's 3:30.
And what time is the show?
8:30.
[vocalizing]
I don't think it's a good idea.
That's my feeling.
I want to bring you to Cez,
just so you can say to him,
based off of...
You're saying,
based off of how my voice sounds--
Based off of that,
you shouldn't even be talking.
I'm nervous that you'll hurt yourself,
and then...
Can you hear me?
Yeah.
Hey.
Yeah, so we FaceTimed Nasseri in
while we were in with the other doc.
So he was there
looking at all the videos, all the scopes.
Everything was, like, through him.
Yeah, I completely trust
what you're saying, and agree.
The truth is in the singing.
Yeah,  a hundred percent.
[chuckles]
It's there or it's not. Yeah, totally.
Okay, if you're saying
it's detrimental to warm up right now,
then let's not do that.
All good. Thanks, Eric.
All right. Bye, dude.
Just so you know, I've made it very aware
that we have 11 more shows after this.
If we're in any way pushing through
this show to get this show done,
it'll be to the detriment of those.
-We'll have to start thinking about--
-The show scenario. Yeah.
Dr. Nasseri, it's Cez here.
I'm going to merge a call with Eric,
and you've got me and Shawn here.
[Vetro] So, Shawn, any improvement yet?
No.
-Five hours to show time, Cez?
-Yeah, we're 30 minutes to doors.
-Thirty minutes to doors? Why so early?
-'Cause it's a stadium.
Right.
[Nasseri] I was just gonna say,
we've seen people who have said,
"I'm just going to muscle through it",
and they completely hemorrhaged,
and then they needed surgery.
I mean, I know it's a really
overwhelming thing to cancel, but--
[Vetro] I'm gonna step in now and tell you
you have really no voice,
we have 11 shows to go.
For an outside stadium,
you're gonna hurt yourself
for the next 11.
-Yeah.
-[Vetro] What do you think, Shawn?
I don't know. I'm not in a good place
to make any decisions.
[Darke] He's overwhelmed.
And just to be clear,
both of you are saying
we should cancel the show, right?
-[Vetro] We're unanimous on that.
-[Darke] Okay.
Well, we'll get into it this side,
and, um...
Yeah, we'll let you know
on the final decision,
and then we'll update you.
-[Vetro] Okay.
-All right. Thanks, dudes.
Take care.
[slow, reflective music]
See you in a bit, all right?
[sighs]
[breathes deeply]
[sniffles]
[crying softly]
[indistinct clamoring]
[in Portuguese] Canceled!
"It breaks my heart to do this,
but my doctors told me
I cannot perform tonight,
or it would risk
long-term damage to my voice.
I love you all, and I apologize
from the bottom of my heart.
I wish I could be there on stage tonight.
I'll make it up to you
the next time I'm there."
[breathes deeply]
[sniffles]
[water running]
[pensive music]
[phone ringing]
-[sighs, sniffles]
-[Karen] Aw, babe, I'm sorry.
It was a great show last night.
They got to see you there, babe.
It wasn't like...
you haven't been there.
They've seen you.
They've experienced it.
It wasn't like
you've never been there.
You told me you were sick.
You had a bad voice,
but you never told me
it was that serious.
[gentle piano music]
It's fine. You're fine.
It's not the end of the world, babe.
Take a breath.
[whispering] Yeah.
You can't help it.
[breathes deeply]
Love you.
You too, babe. I love you more.
You're good. You've got it.
You've got this, babe.
You know what,
the fans are gonna understand.
Yeah, said you were on vocal rest.
I didn't realize it was that serious.
[inaudible]
[gentle piano music continues]
[mouthing] Both of us.
[imperceptible]
[Shawn] It's so hard in that moment
to be like, "What can you do?"
because there's 40,000 people outside.
And you just feel...
the deepest pit in your stomach.
[sniffles]
Wow, it changes the mood real fast.
[Shawn] When we got to the hotel
and I was up in my room,
I was so upset with the situation,
and then I heard chanting from outside.
[people cheering,
chanting in Portuguese]
[uplifting piano music]
I opened up my window,
and there was
2,000 people in the streets chanting.
[chanting in Portuguese]
And that is, like, beautiful.
[chanting continues]
Right then, I was like, "I can't even...
I can't even believe
how good people are."
Just a really beautiful thing.
[shower running]
[typing on phone]
[automated female voice]
I was upset for a while.
[continues typing]
[acoustic guitar music]
I sat there in the stadium knowing
I was the reason it was all falling apart.
[continues typing]
The hardest part is
feeling like I let them down.
[continues typing]
These next 10 years are when
everything I do is going full speed.
It's like an athlete in their prime.
[strumming intensifies]
I have to keep going.
[Shawn] The heaviness of the tour
made me want to flip things around
and become more positive, you know?
And I'm writing about anxiety more as...
a companion I have to live with
and less of an enemy
that I'm trying to resist.
-[playing uplifting melody]
-[both singing indistinctly]
♪ Never thought
It would get this far ♪
♪ Never thought it would get this far ♪
♪ Never thought it would get this far
Been around... ♪
Okay, can we just double that, then?
-Double that, I think it's cool.
-Cool.
[playing slow melody]
[Shawn on recording]
♪ You're the only person ♪
♪ I keep coming back to ♪
♪ It's always been you
It's always been you ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah! ♪
[song continues playing]
♪ It's always been you
It's always been you ♪
♪ It's always been you! ♪
I'm really excited
to sing these songs on tour.
All this stuff is so playable,
in the best way.
I want another "Do you know" to come in...
behind it there, like...
And then another third one
to come in there,
like, kind of, a little rise.
[gentle piano music]
When you start an album,
you don't really know what to expect.
So you just have to dive in
and see what happens.
[playing bittersweet melody]
♪ I wonder what it's like to be... ♪
[indistinct]
♪ I wonder ♪
♪ I wonder ♪
♪ I wonder
What it's like to be my friends ♪
♪ I hope that they don't think
That I'll forget about them ♪
♪ I wonder
Why it's so hard to choose ♪
♪ I should go to sleep ♪
♪ I think too much ♪
♪ Right before I close my eyes
The only... ♪
Some sort of little thing
in the back there.
♪ Been dreaming
That you feel it, too ♪
♪ I wonder
What it's like to be loved by you ♪
[Scott] Yeah.
[Shawn vocalizing on recording]
-You felt that there?
-Little pause? Yeah.
[song continues playing]
Hear it now.
How are the horns sounding right now?
[song continues playing]
[emotional drum roll]
[instrumental song section soaring]
[on recording]
♪ I wonder when it starts... ♪
[women cheering]
[men talking indistinctly]
[woman laughs]
Is this how we always assembled?
-It's our thing.
-Okay, cool.
[man 1] Good times.
It's our last show.
-It's our last show.
-[man 2] And it's sold out.
Sold out, baby.
[Shawn] Oh, ho!
Why do you look so cool?
-[Aaliyah] How are you?
-Fine!
-Hey!
-How you feeling?
-How's it going?
-Mom on FaceTime?
-She is.
-Hi, Mom!
I'll flip it around.
[Shawn] A hundred and five shows...
The last year of my life
has been this tour, and...
it's bittersweet.
It's more sweet than bitter, to be honest.
This makes me so happy,
when I come into the venue,
and it's been weeks,
and all of a sudden,
the "Manny" thing pops up,
and I'm like, "He's coming to town."
["Gimme Shelter"
by The Rolling Stones playing]
[indistinct chatter]
♪ Ooh, a storm is threatening ♪
♪ My very life today ♪
♪ If I don't get some shelter ♪
♪ Ooh, yeah, I'm gonna fade away ♪
♪ War, children ♪
♪ It's just a shot away ♪
-Hey, bro.
-Hey, brother.
[speaking indistinctly]
[Shawn] At the end of this tour,
I'm realizing
this is something
I want to do for the rest of my life.
[audience cheering]
How do you get to the end
of a very, very intense year...
and want to do it all over again?
At the end of this tour,
I wish I had some profound thing
to say about all this, but...
you know what the truth is?
You walk up on the stage
and you look around and you think...
"I'm just a guy who really loves music.
Time to let go."
New York!
[playing "In My Blood"]
♪ It isn't in my blood ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ I need somebody now ♪
♪ Someone to help me out ♪
♪ Whoa, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Whoa ♪
[song climaxing]
[inaudible]
[Shawn] Until next time. We love you.
Thank you so much for having us.
[audience cheering]
[song fading out]
[gentle piano music playing]
♪ You have
A million different faces ♪
♪ But they'll never understand ♪
♪ Unless you let them in ♪
♪ You've been a million different places ♪
♪ Still unsure where it'll end ♪
♪ Stuck in wonderland ♪
[emotional piano playing]
[chuckles]
Let me record that.
[gentle piano music continues]
♪ You have a million different faces ♪
♪ But they'll never understand ♪
♪ Unless you let them in ♪
♪ You've been a million different places ♪
♪ So give yourself a chance to ♪
♪ Get lost in wonderland ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
[chorus harmonizing]
♪ I wonder ♪
♪ If I'm being real ♪
♪ Do I speak my truth
Or do I filter how I feel? ♪
♪ I wonder ♪
♪ Wouldn't it be nice ♪
♪ To live inside a world
That isn't black and white ♪
♪ I wonder ♪
♪ What it's like to be my friends ♪
♪ Hope that they don't think
I'll forget about them ♪
♪ I wonder ♪
♪ Right before I close my eyes ♪
♪ The only thing that's on my mind ♪
♪ Been dreaming that you feel it too ♪
♪ I wonder what it's like
To be loved by you ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ I wonder what's it like ♪
♪ I wonder what it's like to be loved by ♪
♪ I wonder ♪
♪ Why I'm so afraid ♪
♪ Of saying something wrong
I never said I was a saint ♪
♪ I wonder ♪
♪ When I cry into my hands ♪
♪ I'm conditioned to feel
Like it makes me less of a man ♪
♪ And I wonder if someday
You'll be by my side ♪
♪ And someday
That the world will end up all right ♪
♪ I wonder ♪
♪ Right before I close my eyes ♪
♪ The only thing that's on my mind ♪
♪ Been dreaming that you feel it too ♪
♪ I wonder what it's like
To be loved by you ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ I wonder what it's like ♪
♪ I wonder what it's like
To be loved by you ♪
[song continues]
♪ I wonder what it's like
To be loved by you ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ I wonder what it's like
To be loved by you ♪
♪ I wonder what it's like to be loved by ♪
♪ Right before I close my eyes ♪
♪ The only thing that's on my mind ♪
♪ Been dreaming that you feel it too ♪
♪ I wonder what it's like
To be loved by you ♪